advancemed.com.au 2018-09-06

# Privacy | AdvanceMed

## Who we are

We are AdvanceMed a Registered Trading Name of Great Mynds Pty Ltd in Australia ABN 

Great Mynds Pty Ltd

Trading as AdvanceMed

ABN 13 613 634 343

Our website address is: https://www.advancemed.com.au

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

AdvanceMed takes all reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information we hold is kept secure, accurate and up-to-date. Only the managers of AdvanceMed have access to this information and are required to respect the confidentiality of personal information.

AdvanceMed utilises advanced web security methods to safeguard against unauthorised disclosures of information, including a Managed WordPress host.  However, users are reminded that the transfer of information across any media may involve a certain degree of risk and no database is completely secure from unauthorised access.

### Disclosure by users

Users are reminded that they are bound by medical privacy standards when using interactive components on the site such as discussion boards. Users should be careful not to disclose identifiable patient information and if this information is accidentally revealed, other users are bound not to reveal that information to any other person.

### Links to other websites

AdvanceMed provides links on the website to other websites. These sites are not managed by AdvanceMed and we cannot accept responsibility for the contents or operators of those sites. We don’t provide any information about users to these sites, nor does any such information automatically pass to them when users link to them. Before users disclose any personal information for another site they should read the Terms of Use and Privacy Policy for that site.

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact forms

Information collected via contact forms is stored on our site.  Depending on the type of form information may be sent to our customer email resource management system or via our email provider so we can be informed about your contact and provide you with the information you require.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

As is the case of many websites we install analytics codes and tracking to determine and improve the success of our site, specific posts and pages and products.

## Who we share your data with

AdvanceMed uses other software as a service product in order to provide a better user experience.  Data may be shared securely through these services, which currently include:

  * MailChimp for email newsletters and campaigns
  * Teachable for online courses
  * Our email service (hosted in Australia via VentraIP)
  * Xero accounting software

We will only every provide information about you to 3rd parties with your express permission and on the basis that such 3rd parties also provide options for you to unsubscribe and delete any information collected.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

Subscribers information is sent to MailChimp.

### How we protect your data

We protect your data by only using secure services and reliable software.  Our site is securely hosted within Australia with a dedicated WordPress Managed Hosting Service.

### What data breach procedures we have in place

Should there ever be a data breach we have back-ups of all data and the ability to rapidly delete or reset any user data, for e.g. passwords, that may be available online and be used to exploit our users.

### Have you done a Risk Review about Data?

Yes. We have.  The type of data collected by our site and services poses minimal use to you the user through interaction with AdvanceMed.  The biggest potential risk in a data breach is likely to be any password you use.  For this reason, we  **strongly suggest** that you do not use the same password on this site that you may use for some other purpose where if utilized this password could pose the risk of significant damage, for e.g. banking passwords or social media profile passwords.
